伙计们  你们猜怎么了  什么
Guys, guess what?  What?
我知道时间紧迫  但我们决定要办万圣节派对
I know it's last minute, but we decided to have a Halloween party.
很好  太棒了
Good!  Great!
所有人都得变装  我没办法参加
And everybody has to wear costumes.  I can't make it.
少来了  一定会很好玩的
Come on, it'll be fun.
我会去的
I'll be there.
反正那天上课时我也要变装
I have to wear a costume to my classes that day anyway.
你不会打扮成恐龙吧
Tell me you're not gonna dress like a dinosaur.
我怎么会连续两年的扮相一样
Not two years in a row.
我会去的  但我不会变装
I'll come to the party, but I'm not dressing up.
你得变装才行
You have to.
不行  万圣节太愚蠢了
No way. Halloween is so stupid.
变装  假装自己是另一个人
Dressing up, pretending to be someone you're not.
你可是个演员
You're an actor.
罗斯  你会带蒙娜来吗
Ross, are you gonna bring Mona?
我会的
Yeah, I think I will.
你在婚礼上认识的那个漂亮女孩  对
The hot girl from their wedding?  Yeah.
我给她出几个变装的点子
If she needs any ideas for costumes,
她可以扮成比基尼模特
she could be a bikini model...
或风骚护士  或性感啦啦队长
...or a slutty nurse, or a sexy cheerleader.
或是《德州电锯杀人狂》里的皮脸
Or Leatherface from Texas Chainsaw Massacre.
不  还是风骚的皮脸好了
No, no, no! Slutty Leatherface.
乔伊不是也在婚礼上跟她眉来眼去的吗
Now, wasn't Joey hitting on her at the wedding too?
没错  他确实对她有意思
That's right, he was hitting on her.
而我把到了她  我猜最优质的男人才能赢
And I got her. I guess the better man won.
拜托  别把她抢走
Please don't take her from me.
《老友记》  第八季  第6集  万圣节舞会
Friends S08E06 The One With The Halloween Party
厄休拉
Ursula!
等一下  是我  菲比
Wait. It's me, Phoebe.
我还以为那里有面镜子  好吧  再见
I thought there was a mirror there. Okay. Bye.
等一下
Wait a second!
你最近有什么情况
So, what's new with you?
没什么  下星期我就要结婚了
Nothing. I'm getting married next week.
什么
What?
婚礼很简单  我们只邀请家人观礼
It'll be a small ceremony. Just family.
他的家人
His.
好吧
Okay.
我为你感到高兴
I'm really happy for you.
等一下  如果你也想来的话
Wait. If you want to come,
我猜应该没关系
I guess that'd be okay.
真的吗  当然
Really?  Sure.
你可以当我"那一天"的妹妹
You could be my sister for the day.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
我朋友今晚要在我以前的公寓
My friends are having a Halloween party tonight
办万圣节派对  你可以来参加
at my old apartment, so you could come.
或许我可以见见你未婚夫
Maybe I could meet the guy you're marrying.
我今晚要去餐馆上班
Well, I'm supposed to work at the restaurant tonight.
我现在就应该在上班  管他呢
I'm supposed to be working now, so who cares!
那是个化装派对  所以你才会穿成这样
By the way, it's a costume party.  So that's why you're...
不是
No.
不过还是谢谢
But thanks.
你应该变装的  我有啊
You're supposed to wear a costume.  I am.
我扮成了花大钱
I am a woman who spent a lot of money
买心爱洋装的女人
on a dress she wants to wear...
因为很快她就穿不下了
...because soon she won't fit into it.
我是猫女
I'm Catwoman,
如果你穿不下  可以把它借给我
who wants to borrow the dress when you're too big for it.
好啊
Okay.
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat!
我可以分糖果给他们吗
Can I give out the candy?
我想跟孩子们打成一片
I really want to be with the kids right now.
自从怀孕之后
You know, ever since I got pregnant
我的母性本能就异常强烈
II have the strongest maternal instincts.
不给糖就捣蛋  急什么
Trick or treat!  Just a minute!
瞧你们啊
Look at you guys!
你是个可怕的巫婆  谢谢
Wow! You are a very scary witch.  Thank you.
你是个好笑的小丑  谢谢
And you are a very funny clown.  Thank you.
你...
And you...
非常符合现在的流行趋势
...are so in style right now.
我在拉夫罗兰的公司工作
I work at Ralph Lauren.
今年秋天流行马术主题
The whole fall line has got this equestrian theme going on.
你应该没看过英国时尚杂志的封面
I don't suppose you saw the cover of British Vogue, but...?
能给我糖果了吗
Could I just have the candy?
好
Yeah.
没问题
Sure.
猫女  我们又见面了
Catwoman. So we meet again.
没错  女超人
So we do, Supergirl.
我是菲比
It's me, Phoebe.
莫妮卡  我能跟你谈一谈吗
Monica, can I talk to you for a second?
谢谢你帮我找来这套衣服
Listen, I appreciate you getting me the costume...
这是你帮他找的吗
You did this to him?
怎么了  我觉得他一定会喜欢
What? I thought he'd love it.
他最喜欢的儿童读物是《绒毛兔》
His favorite kid's book was the Velveteen Rabbit!
绒毛兔是棕白相间的
The Velveteen Rabbit was brown and white!
只有粉红色的兔子装  不然就没得穿了
Well, it was either a pink bunny or no bunny at all.
我本来就不想穿兔子装  没有正好啊
No bunny at all. Always no bunny at all!
你也没有变装
You didn't dress up either?
不  我有  我扮成了钱德勒
Yes, I did. I'm Chandler.
兄弟  你这是怎么了
Dude, what happened?
我怎么会是那个样子  看着
How is that me?  Okay.
我是钱德勒
I'm Chandler.
那真的很像你
That is so you!
我什么时候是那副德行了
When have I ever done that?
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat.
你是我见过最漂亮的芭蕾舞娘  谢谢
You're the prettiest ballerina I've ever seen.  Thank you.
我该再给你一颗糖果
That deserves another piece of candy.
谢谢
Thank you.
就冲这个我也该再给你一些糖果
I have to say, that earns "twotwo" pieces of candy.
我爱你
I love you!
甜心  统统拿去吧
Honey, here, take it all.
莫妮卡  糖果没了
Monica? We need more candy.
刚刚只来了四个孩子  我知道
What? There's only been four kids.  I know.
但有个孩子说她爱我  于是我全部都给她了
But one said she loved me, so I gave her everything.
难怪你会怀孕
No wonder you're pregnant.
你这次扮成什么了
What are you supposed to be?
还记得俄罗斯卫星史波尼克号吗
Remember the Russian satellite, Sputnik?
我扮成了马铃薯  或是"史波多"...
Well, I'm a potato. Or a "spud"...
这是我的天线
...and these are my antenna.
所以史波尼克变成了...
So Sputnik becomes...?
史波多尼克
Spudnik! Spudnik!
原来我不是变装最失败的人
Wow! I don't have the worst costume anymore.
好吧  罗斯扮成了一坨屎
All right! Ross came as doodie.
不  我不是屎
No, I'm not doodie.
对  你是"屎"波尼克
No, spacedoodie.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
你不打算吻我吗  好吧
Aren't you gonna give me a kiss?  Okay, I will.
但我吻了你之后  你得告诉我你是谁
But right after, you have to tell me who you are.
厄休拉  厄休拉的未婚夫
Ursula?  Ursula's fiance?
你是她的妹妹  对
Oh, my god. You're the sister.  Yeah.
我刚刚打了我未来小姨子的屁股
Okay, I just slapped my future sisterinlaw's ass.
是啊  我真蠢
Yeah.  I'm an idiot.
你妈妈在这里吗  我可以打她的屁股
Uh, is your mother here? Maybe I can give her a little slap on the butt.
我妈自杀死掉了  看吧  我就知道
My mother killed herself.  See, and I knew that.
我满身大汗
Now I'm sweating.
瞧啊  我在流汗
Look at me, I'm really sweating.
跟你说话的功夫  汗还在不断往外冒
Now I'm saying, "Look at me," I'm getting even sweatier.
我还是走吧
I think I probably should go.
没事  我们从头来过
No. That's okay. We'll start over.
嗨  我是菲比  我是艾力克
Hi, I'm Phoebe.  Eric.
你为什么要那样子看我
Why are you looking at me like that?
因为汗滴到我眼睛里了  疼得慌
'Cause the sweat's getting in my eyes and its burning.
谢谢  拿去吧
Thank you.  There.
你这是什么  应该还没有正规的命名
So, what are you?  I don't think they have a name for it.
我一紧张就会满身大汗
I get nervous, and I sweat like crazy.
不  我是指你的服装  我扮成了太阳系
No, I meant your costume.  I'm a solar system.
是我的学生们帮我做的  我教二年级
Yeah, my students helped me make it. I teach the second grade.
我可喜欢二年级了  真的吗
I love the second grade.  Really?
比一年级好多了
Yeah! It's so much better than first grade
一年级什么也不懂
when you don't know what's going on
也比三年级好
and definitely better than third grade.
三年级的尔虞我诈  勾心斗角
With all the politics and the mind games.
你是做哪一行的  我白天做按摩师
So, what do you do?  I'm a masseuse, by day.
你不必陪我  我觉得很开心
You don't have to stand here with me.  I'm having fun.
我为你跟厄休拉感到高兴
I'm excited for you and Ursula.
我觉得自己很幸运  她太棒了
I feel very lucky. She's great.
她是我见过最漂亮的女人
I think she's the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.
谢谢你
Thank you.
乔伊  什么事
Hey, Joey?  Yeah?
你看漫画书吧  我是专家
You read comic books, right?  Exclusively.
如果猫女跟女超人打架  谁会赢呢
Who do you think would win in a fight, Catwoman or Supergirl?
当然是猫女  是吧
Catwoman, hands down.  Yeah.
但你跟菲比  我赌菲比会赢
Between you and Phoebe ? I'd give the edge to Phoebe.
什么  真的吗  你开什么玩笑
What? Really?  You kidding?
菲比在街上混过  好吗
Phoebe lived on the street, okay?
而且她生起气来跟疯婆子一样
Plus, she's got a crazy temper.
她没有站在我后面吧
She's not right behind me, is she?
不  你很安全
No, you're fine.
我能打倒瑞秋吗  我不确定
Could I take Rachel?  I'm not sure.
什么  少来了  我很强悍的
What? Come on, I am tough!
用拳打我这里  用全力
Punch me right here, as hard as you can!
别激动  你为什么这么当真呢
Will you relax?! What are you taking this so seriously for?
那不重要  真的吗
It doesn't matter.  Really?
如果我说罗斯或钱德勒能打倒你呢
What if I told you Ross or Chandler could beat you up?
我会说"姑娘  别闹了"
I would say, "Woman, please."
厄休拉的未婚夫人真的很好
Ursula's fiance is really sweet.
他是老师  他会做义工
He's a teacher, he does all this volunteer work.
通常我不喜欢爱流汗的男人
Normally, I don't like sweaty guys.
但我愿意帮他擦汗
But I could just mop him up.
天啊  菲比  怎么了
Oh, my God, Phoebe?  What?
你在暗恋你姐姐的未婚夫
You're getting a crush on your sister's fiance.
不  我才没有  是你
No, I'm not, you are!
她的脾气上来了
Here comes the temper.
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat.
知道吗  亲爱的  我们没有糖果了
You know what, honey? We're actually out of candy right now.
但已经有人去买了
But someone just went to get some.
我改给孩子们钱  但我的钱也都给光了
And I've been giving out money, but I'm out of that too.
我可以开张支票给你吗  好吧
Can I write you a check?  Okay.
好吧  你叫什么名字
Okay. What's your name?
李兰妮·马尤拉诺法维奇
Lelani Mayolanofavich.
好吧  我直接写上"现金支票"
Okay, I'm just gonna write this out to "cash."
嗨  蒙娜
Hi, Mona.
乔伊一定会很兴奋
Joey's gonna be thrilled.
他就希望你扮成风骚护士
He was hoping you'd be a slutty nurse.
事实上我只是普通护士
Actually, I'm just a nurse.
你以为我听了这话会觉得丢脸
You'd think that would embarrass me,
但我已经丢够脸了
but you see, I'm maxed out.
你来了  等一下
You made it.  Wait.
你是马铃薯  我是史波多
You're a potato?  Well, I'm a spud...?
还有天线...你是史波多尼克  答对了
And the antenna... You're Spudnik!  Yes!
娶她吧
Marry her.
这个问题有意思
Okay. Here's a good one for you.
罗斯跟钱德勒打架谁会赢
Who do think would win in a fight between Ross and Chandler?
我没办法回答  钱德勒是我老公
I can't answer that. Chandler's my husband.
罗斯会赢  对
So Ross?  Yeah.
嘿  美女  你好  帅哥
Hey, beautiful.  Hello, handsome.
天啊
Oh, God.
瞧你们真甜蜜  你们什么时候认识的
Look at you two. When did you guys meet?
两个星期前  就两个星期
Two weeks ago.  Two weeks? That's it?
我知道这听起来很疯狂  我不是个冲动的人
Yeah, I know. It sounds crazy, and I'm not impulsive, but...
但是  她很完美  我们有很多共通点
She's just so perfect and we have so much in common.
真的吗
Oh, really?
我们都是老师
We're both teachers.
我们都参加了和平工作团
And we were both in the Peace Corps.
真的吗
Peace Corps, really?
我们在乌拉圭做义工时
In fact, when we were building in Uruguay,
只相距两个小镇远  却从来没见过面
we were two towns apart and we never met.
对  我刚到时那里一片荒芜
Yeah. It wasn't a town when I got there,
但我离开时那里已经是个小镇了
but it was a town when I left.
我们去一醉方休吧  没问题
Shall we get me really drunk?  Sure.
你好  粪团
Howdy, doodie.
真搞笑
That's funny, yeah.
你是屋里最搞笑的家伙
You're the funniest man here
穿着你太太帮你挑的兔子装
in a bunny costume his wife made him wear.
别激动  你看起来有点脸红（被冲走）
Relax, man. Relax. You're looking a little flushed.
我们的问题看来有解了
I think we might find out the answer to our question.
什么问题
What question?
莫妮卡跟我在讨论
Monica and I were talking about
你跟罗斯打架谁会赢
who could kick whose ass in a fight, you or Ross?
那不成问题  你也觉得罗斯会赢
There's no question.  So you think Ross too?
你竟然选罗斯   罗斯真的很强壮
You picked Ross?  Ross is really strong.
他是你们三个之中最壮的  乔伊除外
He's the strongest out of all three of you. Except for Joey.
我不敢相信你没有选我
I can't believe you didn't pick me.
她说得对  我的确比你壮
In her defense, she's right. I am stronger.
我能灭了你
I would destroy you.
真的吗  你觉得你比我壮吗
Really? You think you're stronger?
你为什么不证明给大家看
Why don't you prove it?
我会证明给你看  像证明公理一样
I'll prove it. I'll prove it like a theorem!
好了  别打了
All right! Stop it!
别打了
Stop it!
别打了  谁都不准在我家打架
Stop! No one's gonna fight in this apartment.
莫妮卡  大家就是来看打架的
Monica, people came to see a fight,
快打给他们看吧  别让人家失望
let's give them one what they came for!
你们可以掰手腕
You guys could armwrestle.
听风骚护士的话
Yeah, listen to the slutty nurse.
你死定了
You're going down.
是吗  你才死定了  永世不得超生
Oh, yeah? You're going further down, downtown!
说真的  你们的叫阵台词太丢人了
Seriously, guys, the trash talk is embarrassing.
甘瑟  你买到糖果了
Gunther, you brought candy.
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much for picking this up.
你真的是太棒了  真的吗
You are so sweet.  Really?
总有一天你会让某个男人
Honey, someday you are gonna make some man
成为全世界最幸运的男朋友
the luckiest guy in the world.
我得走了  不给糖就捣蛋
Got to go.  Trick or treat.
嗨  拿去吧
Hi! Wow! There you go.
我朋友路易斯说你会给钱
My friend Lewis told me you were giving out money.
没错  但现在我们有糖果了
We were, but now we've got candy.
我更想要钱
I'd rather have the money.
那由不得你来选  万圣节快乐
That's not your choice. Happy Halloween!
这不公平
This isn't fair.
你只要披上斗篷
Is it fair that all you did was put on a cape
我就要白送你东西  那公平吗
and I gotta give you free stuff?
闭嘴
Shut up!
你才闭嘴
You shut up!
你不能叫我闭嘴  我刚刚就说了啊
You can't tell me to shut up.  I think I just did.
我又想说了  闭嘴
And here it comes again. Shut up!
瑞秋  我可以  我很厉害的
Rach.  No, I got it. I'm good. I got it.
等一下  我还有一句话要告诉你
Wait a minute, I had one more thing to say to you.
对  闭嘴
Right. Shut up.
你是个恶毒的老女人
You're a mean old woman.
等一下  闭...别哭了
Wait! Shut... Don't cry!
我去拿支票簿
Let me get my checkbook!
亲爱的  你不必这么做
Look, honey. You don't have to do this, okay?
你强大的内心才是我最看重的
It's the strength you have inside that means the most to me.
你既忠心又老实  而且还为人正直
You're loyal, and you're honest and you have integrity.
这才是我希望在深爱的男人身上看到的品质
That's the kind of strength I want in a man that I love.
那对我来说毫无意义  来吧
That means nothing to me. Come on!
嗨  骗子
Hi, liar.
他之所以会娶你
You know, the only reason he's marrying you
是因为他以为你说的话都是真的
is because he thinks the things you were saying were true.
有可能是真的  但你在说慌
They could be true.  But they're not.
真假只有一线之隔
Yeah. It's a fine line.
你为什么要说谎  我不知道
Why are you lying to him?  I don't know.
他跟我说自己做过的事  我说我也做过
He said he did all these stuff, I said I did it too.
他就变得很兴奋  我觉得很好玩
and he got so excited, it was really fun.
亲爱的
Honey?
这是个坏习惯  我要你马上戒烟
It's a filthy, disgusting habit, and I want you to quit now!
她帮助很多人戒过烟
She's helped so many people quit smoking.
我们得走了
We'd really better get going.
你今晚还得参加教会的聚会  对
Right. You have a church group meeting tonight.  Right.
很高兴能见到你  我也是
It was nice meeting you.  You too.
厄休拉  我很高兴今晚能见到你
And, Ursula, it was really nice meeting you tonight!
菲比快来  兔子大战粪团  我们在等你
Pheebs, come on! Bunny versus doodie. We're waiting!
好吧  一次决胜负  赢的人是英雄
Okay, guys. One match, winner take all.
等一下  赢家有什么奖品
Wait. What does the winner get?
骄傲  跟自尊
Pride.  And dignity.
好吧  你说了算
Okay, if you say so.
好吧  就位  预备  开始
All right, ready, set, go!
加油  加油
Come on!  Come on!
他们都很强
Wow, they're both really strong.
或是一样弱
Or equally weak.
天啊  钱德勒露出他的性感表情了
Oh, God. Chandler's making his sex face.
你累了吗
So you getting tired?
不累  我可以撑一整天
No. I could do this all day.
对  我也是
Yeah. Me too.
但我有点累了  天啊  我累坏了
Getting a little tired, though.  God, I'm exhausted.
这样会让我面子上过不去
This is starting to look really bad for me, okay?
蒙娜就站在那里
Mona's standing right over there.
她在跟乔伊说话  你得让我赢
God, she's talking to Joey! You gotta let me win!
没门  应该是你让我赢才对
No way! If anything you've gotta let me win!
我老婆以为我是软蛋
My wife thinks I'm a wimp!
至少你还有老婆
At least you have a wife.
我三番五次地离婚  搞大别人的肚子
I keep getting divorces and knocking people up.
我还打扮得跟个粪团一样
And I'm dressed as doodie.
你是史波多尼克
You're Spudnik.
少来了  我骗谁呢  我就是粪团
Come on, who we kidding ? I'm doodie.
拜托  她在看我
Please? She's watching.
好吧  谢谢
Fine.  Thanks.
不要啊  太棒了
Oh, no.  Oh, yeah!
我的英雄
My hero!
你真是个怪女人
You're a weird lady.
厄休拉忘了拿皮包
Ursula said she left her purse.
这下放心了  里面装了她祈祷团朋友的电话
What a relief. It has all the numbers for her prayer chain.
是啊
I'm sure it does.
我们婚礼上见了
Guess I'll see you at the wedding.
我可能没办法去参加婚礼了
Listen, I don't think I'm gonna make it to the wedding.
祝你们好运
So I just want to wish you all the luck in the world.
我想我们会幸福的
I think we'll be okay.
一切都很完美  她一直为我保持处女之身
It's so perfect, and she's been saving herself for me.
我不能让你这么被骗下去了  她在说谎
Okay, I can't let you do this. She's lying to you.
什么
What?
她在说谎  我可以证明  稍等
She is lying. And I bet I could prove it. Excuse me.
好吧  不是祈祷团
Okay. Yeah, not a prayer chain.
但看起来像是银行的平面图
But what looks like a detailed drawing of a bank floor plan.
这是她在餐厅当女服务生的名牌
Okay, here's the name tag from where she works as a waitress.
她不是老师  是女服务生
Not a teacher, a waitress.
这是她的驾照
All right, here's her driver license,
她总是在年龄上撤慌
this oughta be good, she always lies about this.
她跟你说她几岁了  她说自己25岁
How old did she say she was?  She told me she was 25.
我都不想拿给你看了
I almost don't want to show you this.
记住  我比她年轻一分钟
Just remember, I'm a minute younger.
我太笨了
I am so stupid.
她当然是在撒谎
Of course she was lying!
她不是老师  根本就没有
She's not a teacher. There's not such a thing
"儿童间谍绝密小学"这种学校
as the top secret elementary school for the children of spies.
不  你不笨
No, you're not stupid.
我也不聪明
I'm not smart.
我只是想冲动一把
I just wanted so much to be impulsive for once.
找点浪漫
To be romantic.
很好  你想要冲动跟浪漫  这样没错
That's good. You should be impulsive and you should be romantic.
只是你找错了对象
Just... you did it with the wrong person.
什么  真的很奇怪  你们长得那么像
What?  It's weird, two people look so much alike.
心地却完全不同
And so different.
艾力克  我们走吧
Eric! Let's go!
我得去解决这个问题  没错  应该的
Better go deal with it.  Yeah, you should.
快点  我得去祷告
Hurry up! I gotta pray!
我得给那孩子50块  他才不哭了
Well, I had to give the kid 50 bucks to stop crying.
那还不赖
That's not so bad.
我还得当他的女朋友  陪他走家串户
No, I also had to go to a couple houses with him as his girlfriend.
我真的不会应付小孩子
I am just awful with children.
你跟孩子们相处得很好
Come on. You're good with kids.
只是小孩子在万圣节都会抓狂
They're just crazy on Halloween.
他们贪心地想多拿一些糖果
They're all greedy, hopped up on sugar.
就因为这个吗  当然
Really? That's all it is?  Absolutely.
万圣节最难搞了
Halloween is the worst.
除了圣诞节  跟他们的生日
Except for Christmas. And their birthdays.
他们在暑假也会抓狂
Kinda get a little crazy during the summer too.
还有他们肚子饿跟想睡觉的时候
And any time they're hungry or sleepy.
小孩子很难缠  祝你好运
Kids are tough. Good luck with that.
你输了  我很遗憾
Look, I wanted to tell I'mI'm sorry you lost.
我得告诉你一个秘密  是我放水让他赢的
Listen, I've got a secret for ya. I let him win.
那是秘密还是谎话
Was that a secret, or a lie?
不  我让他...罗斯  什么事
No, I let him... Ross?  Yeah?
麻烦你告诉她我放水让你赢
Would you tell her I let you win, please?
钱德勒"放水让我赢"
Yeah. Chandler "let me win."
不  钱德勒真的好壮
No, Chandler's really strong.
我的手好酸  护士
My arm is so sore. Oh, nurse?
我很强壮  我要证明给你看
I am strong. I'll show you.
钱德勒  拜托
Chandler, please.
怎么了  你害怕吗
What's the matter? Are you scared?
放马过来吧  大兔子
Let's go, big bunny!
一  二  三  开始
One, two, three. Go!
我想自杀
I'm gonna kill myself!